behr.com 2019-06-09

# Behr Process Corporation Online Privacy Policy | Behr

**Behr Process Corporation** (” **Behr** ,” “we,” “us”) Behr Process Corporation ("Behr," "we", "us") is concerned about online privacy issues, and wants you to be familiar with how Behr collects, uses and discloses your information in connection with our online business. Accordingly, we have created this Privacy Policy to describe our practices in connection with information that we collect through websites operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “Sites”), through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “Apps”), through our social media pages and apps located at [Facebook (<https://www.facebook.com/BehrPaint/>), Twitter (<https://twitter.com/behrpaint>), Pinterest (<https://www.pinterest.com/behrpaint/>), and Instagram ([https://www.instagram.com/behrpaint](https://www.instagram.com/behrpaint/))] (collectively, our “Social Media Pages”) as well as through HTML-formatted email messages that we send to you that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, including the Sites, Apps and our Social Media Pages, the “Services”). Except as otherwise expressly provided herein, this Privacy Policy does not govern our collection of information through any web site, or by any other means, other than through the Services; nor does this Privacy Policy govern the collection of information by any of our Affiliated Entities (as defined below) or by third parties.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy before using the Services or submitting your personally identifiable information to us. Your use of the Services signifies that you agree with all terms of this Privacy Policy, so please do not use the Services if you disagree with any part of this Privacy Policy.

## Policy Modifications

Behr reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. In the event that Behr makes a material change to this Privacy Policy, it will be posted here. We encourage you to check this page regularly because your continued use of the Services following any changes to the Privacy Policy will be deemed to constitute your acceptance of such change. You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page.

## Notice Regarding Use of the Services by Children

The Services are not directed to children under the age of eighteen (18), and we request that children do not provide personally identifiable information through the Services. 

## How We Collect and Use Personally Identifiable Information

We will collect personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, postal address, telephone and mobile numbers, email address, credit card number or other payment number, profile pictures, or social media IDs when you voluntarily provide it to us through the Services such as when you create an account or profile, order or register a product, order literature, enter contests or incentive programs, sign up for newsletters, download an App, participate in a survey, contact customer service, or otherwise interact with the Services. We may receive your personally identifiable information from other sources, such as public data bases; joint marketing partners; social media platforms; from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected on social media platforms; as well as from other third parties. For example, if you elect to connect your social media account to your Site account, certain personally identifiable information from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include personally identifiable information that is part of your profile or your friends’ profiles. 

We use your personally identifiable information to provide the services you request from Behr such as responding to product information requests; registering products; fulfilling orders for parts, products or customer service; initiating refunds; administering contests or incentive programs; and facilitating on-line product visualization applications and preferred products catalogs. We also use personally identifiable information to send you news about our products and promotions, to conduct online surveys, contests, other similar promotions or incentive programs via email, telephone or postal mail, and to notify you of special events and advertising that you might be interested in. Please see the “Sweepstakes, Contests, and Other Promotions” section below for more information on participating in such activities. Further, we may also use personally identifiable information to send you important information regarding the Services, changes to our terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information. Because this information may be important to your use of the Services, you may not opt-out of receiving such communications. In addition, we may use the information to improve Behr’s online and other services, such as through customer service and product support, to understand consumer preferences in developing product improvements and innovations. We may also use your personally identifiable information for internal business purposes, such as optimizing users’ Services experiences and analyzing, managing and expanding our businesses. If you apply for employment with Behr, we may use the personally identifiable information you supply to process your job application. 

The Services may offer a feature that allows you to send an electronic postcard or otherwise share a message with a friend. If you choose to use this feature, we will ask you for the recipient’s name and email address, along with the text of any message you choose to include. By using this feature, you are telling us that you are entitled provide us with the recipient’s name and email address for this purpose. 

We may also use your personally identifiable information: (i) as necessary or appropriate under applicable law; (ii) where we determine that such use is necessary to comply with the request of a law enforcement or regulatory agency or other legal process; (iii) to protect our operations or those of any of the Affiliated Entities; (iv) to protect the rights, privacy, property, interests or safety of Behr, the Affiliated Entities, Services visitors, customers, business partners, employees or the public; (v) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain; (vi) to enforce our Terms of Use; and (vii) to respond to an emergency. 

## How We Collect and Use Other Information

We may also collect other information that does not reveal your specific identity or directly relate to an individual through the Services (“other information”), such as your postal or Zip code, date of birth, gender, IP address, domain name, URL, browser and operating system, a record of the Services pages you visited, App usage data, physical location and information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies.

We and our third-party service providers may collect other information in a variety of ways, including: 

  * **Through your browser or device:** Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version and the name and version of the Services (such as the App) you are using. We use this information to ensure that the Services function properly.
  * **Through your use of the Apps:** When you download and use an App, we and our service providers may track and collect App usage data, such as the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number.
  * **Using cookies:** Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Services, pages visited, language preferences, and other traffic data. We and our service providers use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, and to personalize your experience while using the Services, as well as for online tracking purposes. We can recognize your computer to assist your use of the Services. We also gather statistical information about the usage of the Services in order to continually improve their design and functionality, understand how the Services are used and to assist us with resolving questions regarding the Services. We also partner with third party sites and ad networks to manage and display content and advertising on other websites. Our ad network partners may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on our websites or other websites to provide you targeted and relevant advertising that may be of interest to you. These websites may include search engines, social media sites, video streaming sites, email sites, blogs and general interest websites. We may also use cookies in online advertising to track responses to our advertisements, and we may use cookies to track how you arrived at our site from another website to improve your on-line experience with us. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies, or be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. You may also wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html>. However, if you do not accept these cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Services. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer and you may need to log in every time you visit the applicable Services. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs. Please be aware that even if you change your browser settings to not accept cookies, you may see “contextual” ads from us on sites that you visit. Contextual ads are ads shown to you based on the context of the specific site you are visiting. We may be partnering with these third-party sites to serve advertising based on content we know our consumers may be interested in. 
  * **Using pixel tags and other similar technologies:** Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used in connection with some Services to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Services (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Services and response rates.
  * We do not respond to browser do-not-track signals at this time.
  * We use Google Analytics, a Google service that uses cookies and other, similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the Services and report on activities and website trends. We also use an enhancement to Google Analytics called “Demographics and Interest Reporting,” through which Google provides us with information about our users’ demographics (e.g., age, gender) and interests. This information, which Google may collect by tracking a user’s behavior across third-party websites, helps us to learn more about our users. You can learn about Google’s practices in connection with this enhanced tracking and opt out of it by visiting www.google.com/settings/ads or by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.
  * **Using Adobe Flash technology (including Flash Local Shared Objects ("Flash LSOs")) and other similar technologies:** We may use Flash LSOs and other technologies to, among other things, collect and store information about your use of the Services. If you do not want Flash LSOs stored on your computer, you can adjust the settings of your Flash player to block Flash LSO storage using the tools contained in the Website Storage Settings Panel. You can also control Flash LSOs by going to the Global Storage Settings Panel and following the instructions (which may include instructions that explain, for example, how to delete existing Flash LSOs (referred to “information on the Macromedia site), how to prevent Flash LSOs from being placed on your computer without your being asked, and (for Flash Player 8 and later) how to block Flash LSOs that are not being delivered by the operator of the page you are on at the time). Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications, including, potentially, Flash applications used in connection with the Services or our online content.
  * **IP Address:** Your "IP Address" is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP Address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Services, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications and other services. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels of the Services, helping diagnose server problems, administering the Services and identifying your device’s approximate physical location.
  * **Physical Location:** We may collect the physical location of your device by, for example, using satellite, cell phone tower or WiFi signals. We may use your device’s physical location to provide you with personalized location-based services and content. We may also share your device’s physical location, combined with information about what advertisements you viewed and other information we collect, with our marketing partners to enable them to provide you with more personalized content and to study the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. In some instances, you may be permitted to allow or deny such uses and/or sharing of your device’s location, but if you choose to deny such uses and/or sharing, we and/or our marketing partners may not be able to provide you with the applicable personalized services and content.
  * **From you:** Information, such as your preferred means of communication is collected when you voluntarily provide it. Unless combined with personally identifiable information, this information does not personally identify you.
  * **By aggregating information:** Aggregated personally identifiable information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Services, (for example, we may aggregate personally identifiable information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code).

We may use and disclose other information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat other information as personally identifiable information under applicable law, then we may use it for all the purposes for which we use and disclose personally identifiable information.

In some instances, we may combine other information with personally identifiable information (such as combining your name with your geographic location). If we do combine any other information with personally identifiable information, the combined information will be treated by us as personally identifiable information in accordance with this Policy.

## How We Share Personally Identifiable Information

Behr may share personally identifiable information collected via the Services with Affiliated Entities or other third parties as described below. You should also be aware that personally identifiable information about you may be transferred to or received by Affiliated Entities or third parties in the U.S. or in other countries, which countries may have different privacy regulations than those applicable in the country where you reside.

  * _Affiliated Entities._ We may share personally identifiable information with our parent, subsidiaries and affiliates worldwide (collectively, “Affiliated Entities”) for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, including to permit such Affiliated Entities to send you marketing materials. If you wish to opt-out from our sharing of your personally identifiable information with Affiliated Entities for their marketing purposes, please see the “Choice: Opt Out” section below for information on how to opt-out.
  * _Service Providers._ We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and the Services or to administer activities on our behalf, such as sending emails, hosting dealer locater sites, providing order fulfillment, conducting advertising or customer service, and administering contests or incentive programs. We may share personally identifiable information with these third parties for those business purposes. For instance, if you request a brochure, we may share personally identifiable information about you with fulfillment and management agencies to complete your request.
  * _Dealers and Retailers._ We may share personally identifiable information with third parties that offer our products for sale. The third-party dealer or retailer may contact you directly by email, phone or postal mail. If you wish to opt-out from our sharing of your personally identifiable information with such third parties for their marketing purposes, please see the “Choice: Opt Out” section below for information on how to opt-out. If you provide any personally identifiable information to such a third party through its website or otherwise, your transaction will occur with the third party (and not on the Services) and the personally identifiable information you provide will be collected pursuant to the privacy policy of that third- party. Behr recommends that you review the privacy policy of third parties who may contact you about Behr or Affiliated Entities’ products or services.
  * _Other Third Parties._ We may share personally identifiable information with unaffiliated third parties, including dealers and retailers discussed above, to permit such third parties to send to you marketing materials. If you wish to opt-out from our sharing of your personally identifiable information with third parties for their marketing purposes, please see the “Choice: Opt Out” section below for information on how to opt-out.
  * _E-mails to Friends._ Please note that any personally identifiable information you provide in connection with sending an electronic postcard or other message to a friend through the Services, such as your name and your e-mail address, will, of course, be disclosed to your friend.
  * _Social Media._ We may share any personally identifiable information you provide with your friends associated with your social media account, to other website users and as well as to your social media account provider, in connection with your social sharing activity, such as if you connect your social media account to your Services account or log-into your Services account from you social media account. By connecting your Services account and your social media account you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the social media site’s privacy policy. If you do not want your personally identifiable information shared with other users or with your social media account provider, please do not connect your social media account with your Services account and do not participate in social sharing on the Services.
  * _Promotions._ We may share the personally identifiable information you provide in connection with sweepstakes, contests and similar promotions with third party sponsors of such promotions (irrespective of whether such promotions are hosted by us), or otherwise in accordance with the rules applicable to such promotion. Please see the “Sweepstakes, Contests, and Other Promotions” section below for more information on participating in such activities.
  * _Assignment._ We may transfer information that we collect from Services users to an Affiliated Entity or a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of Behr’s business, assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * _Other Disclosures._ We may share your personally identifiable information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (i) under applicable law, which may include laws outside your country of residence; (ii) to comply with the request of a law enforcement or regulatory agency (including agencies outside your country of residence) or other legal process; (iii) to protect our operations or those of any of the Affiliated Entities; (iv) to protect the rights, privacy, property, interests or safety of Behr, the Affiliated Entities, Services visitors, customers, business partners, employees or the public; (v) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain (vi) to enforce our Terms of Use; and (vii) to respond to an emergency.
  * _Co-Branded Pages._ From time to time, we may enter into a special relationship with another company that is not owned by or affiliated with Behr to provide additional features on the Services, such as co-branded pages. Both Behr and the third-party collect personally identifiable information on these co-branded pages. Behr’s collection, use and disclosure of the personally identifiable information are subject to this Privacy Policy, and the third party’s collection, use and disclosure of the personally identifiable information are subject to its privacy policy. You should review the privacy policies posted on these co-branded pages to understand how personally identifiable information collected through these pages will be collected and used.
  * _Purchases._ We may use third-party payment services (each, a “Payment Service”) to collect payments made through the Services. If you wish to make a payment through the Services, you will be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the Payment Service (or the Payment Service’s service providers) and not by us (such page, the “Payment Service Page”). Any personally identifiable information that you provide through the Payment Service Page will be collected by Payment Service and not by us, and will be subject to Payment Service’s privacy policy, rather than this Policy. Behr has no control over, and shall not be responsible for, Payment Service’s use of information collected through the Payment Service Page.

## User Generated Content Functions

Certain pages on the Services, including our Social Media Pages, enable users to create their own profile page or submit their own content (for example, message boards, forums, chat functionality and blogs, among other services). Any information you disclose in connection with such services may be publicly available and be read, collected, or otherwise used by anyone who visits the page on which you have chosen to comment, and you should exercise caution in deciding whether to disclose your information there. Behr cannot prevent such publicly-available information from being used by others in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy and safety, and is not responsible or liable for the results of any postings or the use or disclosure of any information that you disclose via such postings.

## Choice: Opt-out

If you do not wish to receive marketing-related emails from us, or if you would prefer that we do not share personally identifiable information about you collected via the ( _Services or otherwise_ with Affiliated Entities) or other third parties for such Affiliates Entities’ or other third parties’ marketing purposes, you may opt-out of receiving such marketing-related emails and from such sharing by visiting www.behr.com and clicking on the Envelope Icon in the gray area above the footer of the home page where you may elect to unsubscribe from receiving marketing-related emails from us. This election will also opt you out of allowing us to share personally identifiable information about you with our Affiliated Entities or unaffiliated third parties for such Affiliated Entities' or unaffiliated third parties' marketing purposes.

If you are currently receiving emails from Behr and wish to unsubscribe, you can also click on the unsubscribe link in the footer of the email.

We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that, if you opt-out as described above, we will not be able to remove personally identifiable information about you from the databases of Affiliated Entities or other third parties with which we have already shared your personally identifiable information as of the date on which we implement your opt-out request. If you wish to cease receiving marketing-related emails from such Affiliated Entities or other third parties, please contact such Affiliated Entities or other third parties directly or utilize any opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or marketing-related emails.

## Sweepstakes, Contests, and Other Promotions

We may operate sweepstakes, contests, raffles and similar promotions through the Services that may require online registration with us or with third-party sponsors of such promotions. You should carefully review the rules of each promotion in which you participate through the Services, as they may contain additional important information about Behr’s or a sponsor’s use or disclosure of your personally identifiable information. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of personally identifiable information conflict with this Policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control.

## Third Party Services

The Services may contain links to other sites which are not operated by Behr. BEHR IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OR THE CONTENT OF SUCH OTHER WEBSITES, INCLUDING WEBSITES OPERATED BY AFFILIATED ENTITIES. We provide such links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of links on the Services does not imply endorsement of the linked site by Behr. If you provide any personally identifiable information through any such third-party website, your transaction will occur on such third party’s website (and not on the Services) and the personally identifiable information you provide will be subject to the privacy policy of that third party. Behr recommends that you review the privacy policy of third-party websites arrived at from links on the Services.

In addition, we are not responsible for the information collection, usage, disclosure or security policies or practices of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any personally identifiable information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with the Apps or our Social Media Pages.

## Third Party Advertisers

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding goods and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use the Services and other websites or online services, based on information relating to your access to and use of the Services and other websites or online services on any of your devices, as well as on information received from third parties. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags). They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn how to opt out of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Privacy Policy, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/> You may download the AppChoices app at [www.aboutads.info/appchoices](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to opt out in mobile apps.

## Security of Personally Identifiable Information

Behr takes measures designed to protect personally identifiable information collected through the Services against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Unfortunately, however, no security system or system of transmitting data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be entirely secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us in accordance with the "Questions" section below.

For your own protection, we encourage you not to include sensitive personally identifiable information, such as payment card information, in any emails you may send to us. Behr will not request sensitive personally identifiable information in our emails to you.

## Jurisdictional Issues

The Services are controlled and operated by us from the United States, and are not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using the Services you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have data protection rules that are different from those of your country. In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your personal information.

## Questions

If you have any questions about this Policy or how Behr processes your personally identifiable information, please contact us by e-mail through the Customer Service section on www.behr.com.
